Guide to the Donald MacInnis Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Donald MacInnis Papers
1899-2005
RG 204
Yale University Divinity School Library
14
(43 boxes)
The bulk of this collection consists of research files compiled by Donald MacInnis, a prominent historian of missions in China. Correspondence, writings, collected material, and photographs gathered by MacInnis for his book China Chronicles from a Lost Time: The Min River Journals provide extensive documentation of Christian missions in Fujian province. The collection also includes correspondence, writings, and biographical documentation of MacInnis, who was a missionary in China and Taiwan and director of the China Program of the National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., the Midwest China Center, and the Maryknoll China Research Program.
MacInnis, Donald E.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the MacInnis family, 2006
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Chronology
1920 Oct 8 Born in Jefferson, WI
1940-1941 Taught at Anglo-Chinese College, a Methodist senior middle school temporarily based in Yangkow
1942 B.A., UCLA
1942-1946 Military service with Army Air Corps, Army Specialize Training Program (Chinese language) and Office of Strategic Services; service in China as coastwatcher in Amoy, Fujian
1945 Jan Married Helen Paulsen; children: Bruce, Peter, Kristin, Martha
1946 Attended Stanford School of International Relations after discharge from military service
1947-1949 Taught at Fukien Christian University; evacuated in May 1949 due to approach of Communist army
1949-1953 M.Div., Yale Divinity School; ordained as minister of the United Methodist Church
1953-1966 Served as Methodist missionaries in Taiwan
1966-1975 China Program Director, National Council of Churches of Christ in the USA, NY
1975-1980 Director of Midwest China Center, St. Paul, MN
1980-1990 Director of China Research Program and Maryknoll History Program, Maryknoll Fathers and Brothers, Maryknoll, NY
1990 Retired to Brunswick, ME
1990s-2005 Research and writing for book China Chronicles from a Lost Time: The Min River Journals, to be published by EastBridge
2005 Dec 11 Died in Brunswick, ME
Scope and Contents
The largest section of this collection, Series I, Research Files, contains correspondence and materials gathered by MacInnis in connection with his major writing project, China Chronicles from a Lost Time: The Min River Journals. The manuscript for this work was submitted to EastBridge Books. MacInnis gathered documentation and primary sources material from the families of missionaries who had worked in the Min River valley area of Fujian (Fukien) province. According to the agreement made by MacInnis with these families, all original format primary sources that MacInnis received for his project have been transferred to the Yale Divinity School Library's China Records Project collections. The finding aid indicates which collections now contain original format materials that MacInnis received. MacInnis's research files contain extensive photocopies and letters that provide detailed information about both Protestant and Catholic missions in the Min River area.
Series II contains writings by MacInnis and by others. Series III, Personal Papers, contains family and circular letters that document MacInnis's work as a missionary in China and Taiwan, as well as his efforts in the 1990s to raise funds for flood relief in China, and biographical information. The Collected Material in Series IV includes documentation regarding Christianity in the People's Republic of China. The photographs in Series V, Audio-Visual Material, include some that were given to MacInnis by families of the Min River missionaries but they were not well-identified as to source, so have not been transferred to the Library's China Record Project collections.
Arrangement
I: Research Files,1899-2002
II: Writings, 1945-1995
III: Personal Papers, 1948-2005
IV: Collected Material, 1928-2004
V: Audio-Visual Material, 1908-1999
Missionaries -- China; Missions -- China; Fujian Sheng (China) -- History; Missionaries; MacInnis, Donald E.
- Research files, 1899-2002; Series I
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into three sections:
  Materials filed by individual
  Materials filed by topic
  Correspondence and notes regarding sources used by MacInnis in his research
  - Filed by individual
    - Bankhardt, Frederick (Methodist, Yenping), 1917-1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Photocopies of letters from FB
    - Bates, M. Searle, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      "Gleanings from the manuscripts of M. Searle Bates"
    - Bays, Daniel
      - Correspondence, photocopies from Christianity in China, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Conference paper by DB: "The Impact of Early Pentecostalism of Established American Missions in China", 1994 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Beard, Willard (See also RG8)
      - Outlines, draft of DM chapter re.Willard Beard, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - Typescripts of Willard Beard journals and letters, 1902-1906, 1929-1930 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with Kathleen Beard Elmer (daughter); obituaries of Willard and Ellen Beard, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Photocopies of photographs, incl. from Beard papers at YDSL, 1912-1939, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Beckon,Oscar and Fred Nelson (Doug Nelson), 1951, 1984-1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      Correspondence with Doug Nelson (nephew of OB, son of FN); article by FN in "Missionary Messenger"; transcript of interviews: "Oscar Beckon's Missionary Experience"
    - Bishop, Eunice and Merlin (See also RG5 and RG8)
      - Correspondence with Eunice Smith Bishop, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Excerpts from ESM's book, "At Home in China and Around the World"; article re. her sister, Helen Huntington Smith, 1941, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Writings by and about Merlin Bishop, orphanage work, war experiences, 1937-1960, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Printouts of photographs, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Bissonnette, Wesley (See also RG8)
      - Correspondence with Phyllis Smith (granddaughter), notes; correspondence with Chinese individuals regarding travel routes taken by Bissonnette in his evangelization work, with maps., 1995-1996, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Photocopy of journal of Wesley Bissonnette pp. 1-561, 1903-1934 (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
      - Photocopy of journal of Wesley Bissonnette pp. 562-911, index, 1934-1942 (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
    - Bliss, Edward, MD (ABCFM, Shaowu), 1997-2000
      - Correspondence with Edward Bliss Jr., notes, 1997-2000, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - "Physician for Shaowu" - typescript draft biography of Edward Bliss, Sr. by Edward Bliss Jr. (370 pp) (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
      - "Tom Sawyer in China: A Reminiscence" by Edward Bliss Jr. (autobiographical) (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Photograph of Foochow mission circa 1900 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Botjer, George, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      Notes, photocopies from A Short History of Nationalist China
    - Brewster family (See also RG8, incl. papers of Sydney Davidson)
      - Correspondence with Dorothy Davidson Brewster Grayson and Marybelle Brewster Hollister, includes handdrawn map of Old Kutien Methodist Mission, 1992-1995 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - "China Behind the Scenes" by Harold Brewster, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Memoir by Dorothy Davidson Brewster Grayson: "We Had a Call - Memoirs of a Medical Missionary Wife 1933-1965", 1992, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - "Her name was Elizabeth" by Eva M. Brewster (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Brown, G. Thompson (Box 3, Folder 27)
      DM notes and book review re. Brown's Earthen Vessels and Transcendent Power: American Presbyterians in China, 1837-1952
    - Burr, Leona L. (See also RG8) (Box 3, Folder 28)
      DM notes re. Burr's Dear Ones at Home
    - Caldwell family
      - Photocopies of letters from Harry Caldwell to his wife, Belle, 1924-1936 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - "The Troubleshooter' - unpublished autobiography by Harry Caldwell (234 pp), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
      - Diary of Belle Cope Caldwell, photocopied original and transcript, 1940-1944 (Box 3, Folder 32-33)
      - Correspondence with Muriel Caldwell (daughter), 1994-2000 (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Copies of photos from "Blue Tiger" by Harry Caldwell, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Unpublished memoir by Oliver J. Caldwell, "Bird of Heaven: An American Family in Rural China during the Last Years of the Drgaon Throne, 1908-1912." (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Chen, Shiming, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 91)
      Autobiography 1934-2002
    - Ch'i, Hsi-Sheng, 1916-1925 (Box 4, Folder 37)
      DM notes and photocopies from Ch'i's Warlord Politics in China, 1916-1928
    - Cole family, W.B. and Edith
      - Transcript of letters of Edith and W.B. Cole (Methodist, Hinghwa) - primarily letters of Edith to family in U.S.,1910-1913, pp. 158-410 (Box 4, Folder 38-40)
      - Transcript of diary of Winfred Bryan (W.B.) Cole (361 pp.), 1904-1951 (Box 4, Folder 41-43)
      - Correspondence with Ted Cole, son of Edith and W.B. Cole., 1965-1966 (Box 4, Folder 44)
      - Correspondence with Ted Cole; Report by Lois Cole "Uncovering my Missionary Roots in Putian", 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    - Darley, Mary
      - DM notes, photocopies re. Darley's "Light of the Morning: the story of C.E.Z.M.S. work in the Kien-ning Prefecture of the Fuh-kien Province, China" (Box 5, Folder 46)
      - "Cameos of a Chinese City" (photocopy), 1996 Feb (Box 5, Folder 47)
      - Notes/ outline (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Dean, Kenneth (Box 5, Folder 49)
      "Daoist Ritual and Popular Religion in Southeast China"
    - Ding family
      - Interview tapes and notes, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 50)
      - "James and Emily Ding: a Five-Generation Christian Family" (13 page paper); article re. Emily Ding from Foochow News; correspondence with daughters Katherine and Lucy, 1994-1997, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 51)
      - Pamphlets incl. "Memorial Album of James Chen - Alumni Association Anglo-Chinese College" and "You are the Light of the World" (Box 5, Folder 52)
      - Photographs, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - Dunch, Ryan (Box 5, Folder 54)
      "Mission Schools and Modernity: The Anglo-Chinese College, Fuzhou" (typescript paper)
    - Eyestone, James Bruce, 1927-2002, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 55)
      Incl. "Brief Life Record" by J. Bruce Eyestone; photocopy of letter from JBE; correspondence with daughter Josephine Eyestone Allyn; photographs
    - Farley, Malcolm and Neva (Box 5, Folder 56)
      "My Life Story" by Neva Farley (China, Fukien Christian University 1924-1941)
    - Fei Hsiao-tung, 1939, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 57)
      DM notes and photocopies from Fei's Peasant Life in China
    - Funk, Grace (See also RG8), 1906-1912,1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      Correspondence with Jean Andrews (stepdaughter), photocopies of newspaper articles about Grace Funk (original scrapbook in RG8)
    - Giffin family, 1994, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 121)
      "The China Giffins" by Alice Giffin; corres.
    - Hartford, Mabel
      - Drafts of "A Biography of Mabel Corinne Hartford of Dover, NH and Fukien, China and History of North Fukien and Some Min River Missionaries, 1887-1927" by Chester A. Wendell, 1995-1998 (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
      - DM notes, biographical information, photocopies of articles, 1954, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - Hood, George (Box 6, Folder 62)
      DM notes re. book by Hood: Mission accomplished?: the English Presbyterian Mission in Lingtung, South China
    - Humphrey, Pauline and Loren, 1941, 1944, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 63)
      Photocopy of "Account of our Evacuation from Fukien Province, China" by Pauline Humphrey (1944), circular letter from Pauline Humphrey (1941), DM corres. with Pauline and Loren Humphrey, photographs of evacuation of Union High School and Wen Shan Girls' School students
    - Judd, Walter, 1927-1999, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 64)
      Photocopies from Judd papers at Hoover Institution and Minnesota Historical Society; speech by Judd titled "What is the Truth about China?"; correspondence between DM and others re.. Judd; biographical documentation
    - Kellogg et al., 1930-1932 (Box 6, Folder 65)
      DM notes and photocopies of letters from ABCFM missionaries in Fukien to Board in Boston, incl. from E.D. Kellogg, George W. Shepherd, Edward H. Smith, Edward Bliss, L. Christian
    - Kinnear, H.N., 1912 (Box 6, Folder 66)
      DM notes and photocopy of "The Battle of Foochow 1911" by H.N. Kinnear M.D., annual report of Foochow Missionary Hospital, 1912
    - Langhorn, Pat, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 67)
      DM corres. with Pat Langhorne, incl. re. her aunt Martha Wiley and Donal Hsueh, Principal of Foochow College; photocopies
    - Lutz, Jessie, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 68)
      Corres. with Jessie Lutz, lists of missionaries from "The China Mission"
    - McClure family (See also RG 8)
      - Correspondence between MacInnis and McClure children, including Agnes McClure Alden and her daughter, Catherine Alden., 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 69)
      - Photocopies of letters of Robert and Jeanie McClure, with annotations and notes by MacInnis; excerpts re. McClures from book by Leona Burr, 1917-1934, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 70)
      - Photographs of the McClures, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - McGurkin, Edward A., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 72)
      "Profile of Bishop McGurkin 1902-1983"
    - McVay, Bill and Mary Frances, 1995, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 73)
      Corres. with Mary Frances; "Wenshan on Trek" by Helen Smith -re. evacuation of Orlinda Childs Pierce Girls School (Wenshan)
    - Newell, George and Mary Reynolds
      - Photocopied and original letters from George and Mary Newell, incl. re. Carleton in China mission and Union High School, Foochow, 1906-1953 (Box 7, Folder 74)
      - Corres. with Jean Newell Estabrooke (daughter) and Carleton College archivist; biographical information, 1998-1999 (Box 7, Folder 75)
    - Paton, David, 1956,1986, 1987, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 76)
      Letter from Paton to MacInnis, "A conversation with David M. Paton" by Philip Wickeri, Letter to Paton from Bishop Hall, "Faces of Selfhood: The Chinese Experience of Christian Responsibility"
    - Phillips, J. Carlisle, 1991,1996 (Box 7, Folder 77)
      Correspondence with DM; account of JCP visit to Fujian; interview and biography of Yu Sui-duang (orphan born in Kutien, Fujian)
    - Pilley, John and Muriel Caldwell
      - Photocopies of letters from Pilleys, incl. from Anglo-Chinese College, 1938-1949 (Box 7, Folder 78)
      - DM interview notes, corres. with Muriel Pilley; excerpts from "The Hills of Tang" memoir of M. Pilley, 1994, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 79)
    - Riggs family
      - DM correspondence with Riggs family members; notes, 1995-2001 (Box 7, Folder 80)
      - Memoir of Grace Frederick Riggs (1916-1951, 73 pp), 1972 (Box 7, Folder 81)
      - "Agricultural Engineering in Chinese Agriculture: A thesis" by Charles Henry Riggs (120 pp), 1932 (Box 7, Folder 82)
      - Excerpts from letters of Edward and Frances Riggs, Shaowu and Foochow (434 pp), 1947-1950 (Box 7, Folder 83-85)
    - Rinden, Arthur
      - Portion of Arthur Rinden memoir (1926-1951, pp 27-102) (Box 8, Folder 86)
      - DM correspondence with Margaret Rinden Kanost; printouts of photographs, 1992-2002, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 87)
    - Roeder, Paul and Edith Simester (See also RG8), 1988-1995 (Box 8, Folder 88)
      DM correspondence with Paul Roeder re. Edith Simester Roeder
    - Schubert, William (See also RG8), 1983, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 89)
      DM notes for funeral service for William Schubert; excerpts from Schubert's autobiography. ("Revival News" circulars and material re. John Sung revivals placed in RG8)
    - Sheridan, James, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 90)
      DM notes and photocopies from Sheridan's China in Disintegration (1975)
    - Sites, Nathan and Sarah Moore, 1961, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 92)
      Article called "China Mission Mail: The Story of Nathan Sites (photocopied), 3 pg writing on Nathan Sites, obituary of Mrs. Sites
    - Skinner, James E., MD and Sarah L., 1903-1931, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 93)
      Biographical and autobiographical information re. Skinners (Methodist, Yenping); photocopies of circular letters and letters to Methodist Board in NY, 1915-1931; writing "Hope for the Hopeless" re. leprosy work in Fukien
    - Smith, Arthur H., 1899 (Box 8, Folder 94)
      A Chapter from Smith's Village Life in China
    - Sovik, Arne, 1998, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 95)
      Re. Daniel and Esther Nelson and Lutheran airplane; "Last Flight of the St. Paul"
    - Storrs, Charles and Mary (See also RG8)
      - Compilation of documents: "Charles L Storrs, Mary M.G. Storrs: Their Shaowu Mission Years 1904-1943"; supplement to "Shaowu Years" and "Diary Letters" (Box 8, Folder 96)
      - "Mary and Charles Storrs Diary Letters: The Last Tour War Years", 1939 Jan- 1943 Apr (Box 8, Folder 97)
      - Photocopies of letters and photographs, 1923-1941, n.d. (Box 8, Folder 98)
      - DM notes and correspondence with Julia Storrs Strode, 1992-2000 (Box 8, Folder 99)
    - Tomasko, Nancy, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 100)
      Correspondence with DM
    - Wendell, Chester (Box 8, Folder 101)
      Correspondence with DM; see also under Mabel Hartford
    - Whitney, H.T., n.d. (Box 9, Folder 102)
      "Sketch of the Foochow Mission 1844-1888 by H.T. Whitney, M.D."
    - Wilkinson, Frances, 1996-2002, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 103-104)
      Primarily DM correspondence with FW, British missionary and friend in Fukien
    - Worley, Dick, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 104a)
      "A History of the opening of the church among the Tie Chiu People in South China" compiled and edited by Dick Worley
    - Yick, Joseph (Box 9, Folder 104b)
      Conference paper and article titled "Methodist Missionary Contributions to Intercultural Understanding and Diplomacy: The Caldwell Family in Fuzhou and Central Fujian, 1912-1949"
  - Filed by topic
    - ABCFM statistics, history of South China mission, 1930s (Box 10, Folder 105)
    - ACC: Anglo-Chinese College (Box 10, Folder 106)
    - Agriculture and Missions (Box 10, Folder 107)
    - Anglican women missionaries murdered (Box 10, Folder 109)
      Newspaper clipping; memorial written for the two women titled "Faithful unto death"
    - Anti-Cobweb Society (Box 10, Folder 110)
      Foochow Anti-Cobweb Society Season 1948-1949 program handout
    - Anti-Foreignism 1905 Boycott, Anti-missionary, riots, Anti-Christianity, 1905, 1870-1900, 1922-1927 (Box 10, Folder 111)
    - Bandits - Min Valley, 1920s-1940s (Box 10, Folder 112)
    - Boxer rebellion, 1900-1901 (Box 10, Folder 113)
      Min. Shaowu report 1900 Boxers (1 paragraph of a page description), Draft of Miss Hartford, Corresp. (1 letter) from Chester Wendell to MacInnis, Some pages of Min. Walker Boxer report, Some photocopied pages concerning Boxers, Hartwell's Annual Letter of the Foochow Mission (1900)
    - Buddhism, 1916 (Box 10, Folder 114)
      Copy of circular letter from James Bruce Eyestone
    - Canton Christian College, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 115)
    - Catholics in Fujian, 1995, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 116)
      incl. letter to Jean-Paul Wiest; "Lineage and Patterns of Conversion in Guangdong" (paper by Wiest); document in Chinese labeled "Catholic History Fuzhou"
    - Catholic missionaries, 1930-1931, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 117)
      DM notes, photocopies of letters; article "A Brief History of Beijing's Four Churches"
    - Catholic missions: South China - Fujian, 1940-1987 (Box 11, Folder 118)
      Paper by MacInnis titled "Protestant and Catholic missions in South China 1911-1986", notes from writings by others, "Description of a Missioner" by James E. Walsh, excerpts from Ch'iao T'ou Mission Diary", notes concerning "Diary of a Country Missioner" (Maryknoll missions)
    - Children; Missionary children, 1999, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 119)
    - China Christian Advocate: Anglo-Chinese College special issue, 1939 Apr 4 (Box 11, Folder 120)
    - Chinese Christians: Biographies, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 122)
    - Civil war 1930-1931, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 123)
      DM notes
    - Clan warfare, 1907 (Box 12, Folder 124)
      Photocopy of page from The Foochow Messenger: Pagoda Anchorage Evangelistic Work and day Schools 1907. Rev. George H. Hubbard
    - Class system; Imperial reforms/ exams (Box 12, Folder 125)
      Newspaper clipping about class and social distinctions in England, Min. Evacuations and hist. Highlights from Mabel Hartford biog.
    - Communists (Box 12, Folder 126)
    - Currency conversion tables, weights and measures (Box 12, Folder 127)
    - Current Research (Box 12, Folder 128)
      DM notes, photocopies
    - Customs and Postal Service, Foochow, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 129)
      "Notes on the Foo-Chow "Dragon-Boat Stamps"
    - Descriptions of Foochow, Fukien, Shaowu, etc. (Box 12, Folder 130)
    - Devolution, 1927, n.d. (Box 12, Folder 131)
      DM notes re. Min. Shaowu devolution; copy of letter to Frank Gamewell re. reduction in Methodist missionaries
    - Directories of missionaries; General and Business Directory of Shanghai, 1918,1925 (Box 12, Folder 132-133)
    - Dominicans in Fukien (Roman Catholic)
      - DM notes, correspondence re. documents in Dominican archives, Providence; "Kienning-Fu Chronicle" by William F. Cassidy; Dominican statistics, 1948, 1998, n.d (Box 12, Folder 134-135)
      - Photocopies of letters from Dominican archives, 1925-1938 (Box 13, Folder 136-137)
    - Dublin University Far East Mission, 1985, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 138)
    - Dubious Conversions; Fake Christians (Box 13, Folder 139)
    - Ecumenical Relationship; Methodists, Roman Catholics, et al (Box 13, Folder 140)
    - Evacuations, 1911, 1927-1934 (Box 13, Folder 141)
    - Far East and Navan Index (Index to periodical of Columban missions), 1918-1985 (Box 13, Folder 142)
    - Fisher folk Christians, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 143)
    - Floods, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 144)
    - Foochow, 1948-1987, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 145)
      Misc. notes, copies, incl. Foochow Anti-Cobweb Society
    - Foochow Interviews, 1988 (Box 14, Folder 146)
      Typed interviews with Protestant and Catholic Christians, pastors, etc.
    - "The Foochow Mission" (Box 14, Folder 147)
      By Mrs. Arthur Rinden c. 1943 (10 p. photocopied)
    - "Foochow News", 1933-1941 (Box 14, Folder 148)
    - Foochow Christian Schools, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 149)
      Copy from "The Protestant Orphanages of China"
    - Footbinding, 1900-1901, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 150)
      Writing by Miss Minnie Borts (?) "Pagoda Anchorage Girls Boarding School for 1901" (re. foot-binding), Notes re. Leona Burr book, excerpt from "The Light of the morning"; photographs of bound feet
    - "For Christ in Fuh-Kien -The Story of the Fuk-Kien Mission of the Church Missionary Society", 1904 (Box 14, Folder 151)
    - "Forever China", n.d. (Box 14, Folder 152)
      DM notes re. book by Robert Payne; photocopies from works by Graham Greene
    - Fujian, Fuzhou (today), 1984, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - Histories of Fukien, Shaowu, Foochow (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Histories of Chinese religions, 1978 (Box 15, Folder 155)
    - Hua-Shan Massacre (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Idols, paganism (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Kidnappings, arrests (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - Kuliang resort for missionaries, 1909-1934 (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - "Little Flock", 1991-1994, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 160-161)
      Interview notes and collected materials re. "Little Flock" sect
    - Local wars, warfare, warlords (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Maps of Fujian area (Box 16, Folder 163-164)
    - Medical work incl. Opium (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Methodists (Box 16, Folder 166)
      "The Foochow News Anniversary Pictorial Supplement"; "100 Years of Methodism in China"
    - Min Consul - American Consulate